

JOÃO PAIVA

23 years old



Maringá, Paraná, Brazil



joaovmarcotti@hotmail.com

ABOUT ME

Brazilian and 23 years old. Currently living in Maringá, Paraná, Brazil. Electrical engineer and economics final year student. Golden State Warriors and Corinthians fan. In my free time, I like to play basketball with friends, play computer games, watch NBA games or prepare some barbecue with my family. Interested in topics related to finance, data science and machine learning, I am looking for jobs as data scientist, data analyst or BI analyst.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Universidade Estadual de Maringá - UEM

Electrical Engineering Bachelor Degree. March 2018 - June 2023.

Universidade Cesumar - UniCesumar

Economics Bachelor Degree. March 2020 - December 2023.

Fundação Getúlio Vargas - FGV

Business Analytics and Big Data Executive MBA. July 2023 - September 2024.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Inverters Lab Intern

THA Solutions.

July 2022 - November 2022.

Fault diagnosis and repair of photovoltaic inverters.

Elaboration of laboratory control sheets.

M&A Intern

Stonecapital.

February 2023 - June 2023.

Market analysis.

Valuation by analysis of multiples.

Analysis of financial statements.

Customer prospecting (sell-side).

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Development of an electromyography sensor.

April 2019 - April 2021.

Member of the Lapidando Jóias UEM project.

August 2019 - December 2019.

Financial Director of Team Capibaja UEM.

June 2020 - August 2022.

Development of a thermocirculator applied to the Sous Vide culinary technique. March 2021 - April 2023.

Development of an algorithm to redistribute the Ibovespa through Markowitz's Modern Portfolio Theory.

May 2022 - February 2023.

Development and comparison between machine learning models to find the lbovespa's best predictor.

Ago 2023 - Dez 2023.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese - Native. English - Advanced.

SKILLS

- Exploratory data analysis
- Machine Learning
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Word
- Power BI
- Python
- R
- SQL
- Tableau

DATA SCIENCE PORTFOLIO

https://github.com/joaopaivaa/DataSciencePortfolio.

- Classifier Cardiac disease:
- Classifier MNIST;
- Data cleaning NBA games data;
- Exploratory data analysis NBA players data;
- Power BI Retail Store;
- Power BI Super Store;
- · Web Scraping Unicorn Auctions;
- Regressor Boston Housing;
- SQL Company Database.